KELLY COOK

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- 301-356-5915
- ▼ KELLYCOOK20878@GMAIL.COM
- INKEDIN.COM/IN/KELLYCOOK92/
- # HTTPS://KELLYCOOK301.GITHUB.IO/KELLYCOOK/
- O HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/KELLYCOOK301

PROFILE

I am a father, husband, musician, and Maryland native who moved to the Nashville area in 2016 to create a better life for my family. Before making a transition into software development, I worked in the customer service industry for several years. While at Nashville Software School I discovered that I approached creating an app the same way I approached writing a song. While doing both I would always find myself putting great consideration into what the purpose and function of a feature was and how it ultimately served the final product. Those parallels made for some great and very rewarding challenges.

PROJECTS

MYGEARLIST

When it comes to music gear, it can be hard to keep a clean and concise list of what you have. I wanted to make an app that allowed users to keep track of their music gear and any specifics without the hassle of updating spreadsheets. I really had a lot of fun putting this app together! The application was made with React and I used various components to enhance the user experience. Reactstrap was used to generate modals and forms, MDB React allowed access to a wider selection of colors for select buttons and generated posts. The 'delete' and 'edit' FontAwesome icons were used to allow users to delete and edit their respective posts. IconScout provided all of the musical instrument icons, Canva was used to create a logo for the application. And Gimp, an image manipulation program, was used to edit the logo.

https://github.com/kellycook301/GearList

ENSAYAR

In Nashville there are no shortages of great places where acts can rehearse their material. However, many rehearsal spaces do not have an easy way of booking your time. Ensayar (Spanish for "rehearse") is a simple mobile application that allows users to set up an account and manage the times that they would like to practice. The application was made using C#, MVC for the UI, Entity Framework, SSMS, and Dapper. I used various icons and images from IconScout and FontAwesome in terms of styling. https://github.com/kellycook301/finalCapstone

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School

Goucher College, BA Music / Audio Engineering

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville Software School | July 2018 - January 2019 Intensive full-time, six-month software development bootcamp.

- Built browser-based single page applications using React, HTML, CSS and jQuery
- Helped create an e-commerce web application using C#. Entity Framework, and Identity Framework in a group setting
- Application design through white boarding dependencies and building ERD's
- Hands on application of OOP fundamentals through group and individual projects reflecting real world business problems
- Project management/tracking with Github Projects & Issue Tracking
- JavaScript fundamentals leveraging DRY, modular, readable code and reusable components
- Styled applications with CSS Frameworks, Bootstrap and wrote custom styles as needed
- Deployed projects through Github.io
- Leveraged VirtualBox for virtualizing a Windows environment

SENIOR CUSTOMER SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE

Summit Professional Education | June 2016 - July 2018

A continuing education company that provides Physical Therapists, Occupational Therapists, Speech Language Pathologists, Educators, and other Allied and Mental Health professionals with a one-stop shop for all of their CEU needs.

- Spearheaded a video and audio-based tutorial project in order to assist customers with website functionality, features pertaining to a subscription service, and to drive down email and call volume
- Trained new-hires by providing them with knowledge and functions of everyday assignments, how to best utilize task management, and how to establish positive relationships with customers
- Registered customers for Summit subscription services and various workshops around the country in addition to performing daily tasks such as answering incoming calls, responding to emails, returning voicemails, sorting purchase orders, and mailing invoices

EVENING CLASS TECHNOLOGY COORDINATOR

University School of Nashville | January 2016 - March 2016

Three-month, part-time volunteer driven enterprise where attendees can learn anything from iPhone tricks to literature and culinary arts.

- Ensured evening class instructors had adequate methods of presenting their content to their students during the 2016 evening class run
- Worked with various computer operating systems while setting up for presentations, prepared projectors, and computer applications while consulting with evening class instructors

RESTAURANT HOST

Chuy's | January 2016 - June 2016

- Worked with management and employees to ensure smooth daily operations, including table rotation, section cuts, and managing waitlists
- Delivered a professional and courteous disposition towards patrons and fellow employees